{"tossups": [{"question": "Leonard Howell wrote a work important in this religion called The Promise Key. A sect of this religion is based on the teachings of Vernon Carrington, who encourages reading the Bible, a chapter a day. Members are prohibited from eating fish longer than 12 inches in this religion's I-tal (\"eye-tull\") diet. This religion is organized into many (*) \"mansions\" such as the Twelve Tribes of Israel and Bobo Ashanti. God is referred to as Jah in this religion, whose members also revere the Ethiopian leader Haile Selassie. Cannabis is widely smoked and dreadlocks are often worn by practitioners of, for 10 points, what religion practiced by Bob Marley and founded in Jamaica?", "answer": "Rastafarianism", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rastafarianism</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rastafarianism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one play by this author, Lady Cheveley attempts to blackmail Sir Robert Chiltern over his earnings from Suez Canal stocks. In another of this author's plays, Mrs. Erlynne is shamed after claiming that she left the title object in Lord Darlington's room. They wrote that \"each man kills the thing he loves\" in his poem \"The (*) Ballad of Reading Gaol\" (\"redding jail\"). In this author's only novel, Basil Hallward's portrait of the title character ages as its subject stays young. In his most famous play, the bunburyists Jack Worthing and Algernon Moncrieff both pretend to have the title name. For 10 points, name this Irish author of Lady Windermere\u2019s Fan, The Picture of Dorian Gray, and The Importance of Being Earnest.", "answer": "Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills <b><u>Wilde</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One city in this state is known as the \"City of the Five Flags\" due to it having been controlled by five different countries throughout its existence. This state's longest river is the St. John's, and Ernest Hemingway introduced a species of six-toed cats to an island controlled by this state. (*) Britton Hill is this state\u2019s highest point, which is also the southern terminus of the I-95. The retirement community of The Villages is in this state. Dry Tortugas National Park is located in this state, and another national park in this state is bordered by Biscayne Bay and Lake Okeechobee (\"OH-chee-CHOH-bee\"). For 10 points, what state is home to the Everglades and the cities of Jacksonville and Miami?", "answer": "Florida", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Florida</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Florida"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These particles are modeled as having the bouncing behavior of \"pinballs\" in the Drude model. Interactions between these particles and phonons in superconductors create Cooper pairs. Besides antineutrinos, beta-minus decay releases these particles, while beta-plus decay releases their anti-particles. The shining of light on a metal may cause the release of these particles in the (*) photoelectric effect. The charge of this subatomic particle was quantized in Robert Millikan\u2019s oil drop experiment, and Bohr\u2019s (\"BOW-er-z\") model hypothesizes that these subatomic particles stationarily orbit an atom\u2019s nucleus. For 10 points, name these particles that make up an atom along with protons and neutrons and have a negative charge.", "answer": "electrons [or free electrons]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>electrons</u></b> [or <b><u>free electrons</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["electrons", "free electrons"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Trumpets are played loudly during the Tuba mirum section of a requiem by this composer, which they dedicated to the poet Alessandro Manzoni. In one opera by this composer, the song \"Libiamo ne' lieti calici\" (\"lee-bee-ah-no NAY lee-yeh-tee cah-LEECH-ee\") is sung, encouraging the drinking of alcohol. Elephants are sometimes used for the (*) \"Triumphal March\" in an opera by this composer. In another opera by this composer, Alfredo throws his gambling winnings at the feet of Violetta Valery. The Duke of Mantua sings \"La donna e mobile\" describing fickle women in another opera by this composer centered on the title jester. For 10 points, name this composer of the operas La Traviata, Rigoletto, and Aida.", "answer": "Giuseppe Fortunino Francesco Verdi", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Giuseppe Fortunino Francesco Verdi</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Giuseppe Fortunino Francesco Verdi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Fatawa 'Alamgiri was a compilation of the laws governing this empire\u2019s lands. This empire used rockets in a victory against the Adil Shahi dynasty at the Siege of Bidar. This empire invited philosophers to its \"House of Worship\" after the creation of the syncretic religion \"Din-i Ilahi\" (\"deen ee ee-lah-hee\"). This easternmost of the Gunpowder Empires came to power after a victory against (*) Ibrahim Lodhi at the First Battle of Panipat. Shah Jahan built a tomb for his late wife as a ruler of this empire. Babur founded this empire, which reinstated the jizya tax under the rule of Aurangzeb (\"oring-zebb\"). For 10 points, Akbar was a ruler of what Indian Islamic empire?", "answer": "Mughal Empire [accept Moghul Empire or Gurkaniyan Dynasty]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mughal Empire</u></b> [accept <b><u>Moghul Empire</u></b> or <b><u>Gurkaniyan Dynasty</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Mughal Empire", "Moghul Empire", "Gurkaniyan Dynasty"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One novel titled for a character with this name is narrated by Serenus Zeitblom and follows the composer Adrian Leverkuhn. One character with this name punches the Pope in the face, and sees the words \"homo, fuge\" (\"FEW-gay\") written on his arm with blood. One character with this name has his newborn child drowned by Gretchen, and another man with this name asks (*) Helen of Troy \"was this the face that launch'd a thousand ships?\" A character with this name is followed home by a black poodle who turns into Mephistopheles before selling his soul to the devil. For 10 points, give this name of a German scholar whose tragedy was written about by Christopher Marlowe and Johann Wolfgang von Goethe (\"GUR-tuh\").", "answer": "Heinrich Faust [accept Doktor Faustus, Doctor Faustus, or Faust; A Tragedy]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Heinrich Faust</u></b> [accept <b><u>Doktor Faustus, Doctor Faustus,</u></b> or <b><u>Faust</u></b>; A Tragedy]", "acceptable": ["Heinrich Faust", "Doktor Faustus, Doctor Faustus,", "Faust"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A deficiency of the alpha-glucosidase enzyme causes glycogen build-up in these structures. A disease in these structures causes an accumulation of sphingomyelin, which may result in an enlargement of the liver and spleen. Pompe and Niemann-Pick are both diseases of these structures. Proteins bound for this structure are tagged with (*) mannose 6-phosphate by the Golgi apparatus. A mutation on part of the HEXA gene that codes for a subunit of the hexosaminidase enzyme causes Tay-Sachs disease in these organelles. A low pH environment is required for the hydrolytic enzymes located in these organelles. For 10 points, name these organelles which break down cellular waste.", "answer": "lysosomes", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>lysosomes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["lysosomes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Items found in Fred Burke\u2019s bungalow were suspected of use in an event in this city. That event occurred earlier than planned due to Albert Weinshank, and only a German Shepherd named \"Highball\" survived that event. An editor of the Arbeiter-Zeitung newspaper, August Spies, encouraged and led a riot at the (*) McCormick Harvesting Machine Company in this city. In this city, Bugs Moran\u2019s gang was targeted in a massacre named after a holiday. Mrs. O\u2019Leary\u2019s cow is thought to have started an 1871 \"great fire\" in this city. The St. Valentine\u2019s Day Massacre and Haymarket Square riot took place in, for 10 points, what Illinois city?", "answer": "Chicago, Illinois", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Chicago, Illinois</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Chicago, Illinois"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: Description acceptable. Athena lent one man the krotala to aid in the completion of one of these things. That man later shot the sun god Helios while in the Libyan Desert, after which he was lent Helios\u2019 golden boat to help complete another of these things. After the completion of one of these things, a king hid in a wine jar out of fear. That king, (*) Eurystheus, had assigned the completion of these things after one man killed his entire family during a fit of rage. An extra two of these tasks had to be completed due to the man who completed them being paid by King Augeas after cleaning his stables and taking help from Iolaus to kill the Hydra. For 10 points, name these tasks completed by a Greek hero.", "answer": "12 Labors of Hercules [both parts required; accept Heracles for Hercules; accept any answers that mention Hercules completing tasks or labors; prompt on partial answers; anti-prompt on specific labors]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>12 Labors of Hercules</u></b> [both parts required; accept <b><u>Heracles for Hercules</u></b>; accept <b><u>any answers that mention Hercules completing tasks</u></b> or <b><u>labors</u></b>; prompt on <u>partial answers</u>; anti-prompt on specific labors]", "acceptable": ["12 Labors of Hercules", "Heracles for Hercules", "any answers that mention Hercules completing tasks", "labors"], "promptable": ["partial answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Three Steps must be passed on the way to this mountain\u2019s summit, and the area near the top of this mountain is known as the \"Death Zone.\" On this mountain, a dead body known as \"Green Boots\" can be seen. Natives who live near this mountain refer to it as Chomolungma. The Great Trigonometrical Survey estimated this mountain\u2019s elevation in 1856. On this mountain, the Lhotse (\"lote-say\") wall and the (*) Khumbu Icefall provide dangers. This mountain was first climbed by Edmund Hillary and a Sherpa guide in 1953. For 10 points, name this mountain in the Himalayas, whose elevation of 29,032 feet makes it the tallest in the world.", "answer": "Mount Everest [accept Sagarmatha; accept Chomolungma before mention]", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mount Everest</u></b> [accept <b><u>Sagarmatha</u></b>; accept <b><u>Chomolungma</u></b> before mention]", "acceptable": ["Mount Everest", "Sagarmatha", "Chomolungma"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At the beginning of an incident in this location, one man yelled, \"This is what you\u2019ve gotten guys!\" After that incident, Steven Sund resigned and was replaced by Yogananda Pittman as this location\u2019s police chief. Noah Green drove a car into a barricade at this location, killing Officer William Evans. In a speech before an incident at this location, Rudy Giuliani claimed supporters should have \"trial by combat.\" Donald (*) Trump told his supporters to \"walk down to\" this location. Brian Sicknick was killed as a result of an attempted insurrection at this location, making him the first officer to lie in state in this building\u2019s rotunda in 2021. For 10 points, what building, was stormed by rioters on January 6th, and is home to the House and Senate?", "answer": "U.S. Capitol Building [prompt on Capitol Hill or Washington D.C. with \"what specific location\"]", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>U.S. Capitol Building</u></b> [prompt on <u>Capitol Hill</u> or <u>Washington D.C. with \"what specific location</u>]", "acceptable": ["U.S. Capitol Building"], "promptable": ["Capitol Hill", "Washington D.C. with \"what specific location"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This novel begins with a notice that \"persons attempting to find a plot in it will be shot.\" The protagonist of this novel hides a sack of gold in Peter Wilks' coffin to keep it away from two scoundrels. One character in this novel paints himself blue and is called a \"Sick Arab.\" Two characters in this novel put on a play called The Royal Nonesuch and are nicknamed the (*) Duke and the Dauphin. The title character of this novel witnesses a feud between the Grangerford and Shepherdson families, and runs away from home to avoid being \"sivilized\" by his Aunt Sally. For 10 points, what Mark Twain novel is about a boy who travels down the Mississippi River with the slave Jim and his friend Tom Sawyer?", "answer": "The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a painting from this movement, a giant titan\u2019s goblet is shown overflowing with water on a hill. Mount Chimborazo is shown in the back of a painting from this movement which also includes works depicting the eruption of Cotopaxi. An artist from this movement created the series The Voyage of Life and showed the growth and destruction of a city in his The (*) Course of Empire series. Frederic Edwin Church was a prominent member of this movement, whose founder painted a landscape in the Connecticut River valley called The Oxbow. For 10 points, name this school founded by Thomas Cole, named after a New York river.", "answer": "Hudson River School", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Hudson River School</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Hudson River School"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While being imprisoned in Trifels Castle, this monarch famously said \"I am born in a rank which recognizes no superior but God.\" The Treaty of Messina was negotiated by this monarch and Tancred of Lecce to help free their sister, Joan. This monarch was married to Berengaria of Navarre and was captured by (*) Leopold of Austria. This monarch executed many prisoners after the Siege of Acre due to a delay in Saladin\u2019s surrender. His brother, John Lackland, revolted in his absence while this monarch was returning from the Third Crusade. For 10 points, name this English king who was nicknamed \"the Lionheart.\"", "answer": "Richard I [accept Richard alone after \"Lionheart\"; accept Richard the Lionhearted before mention; prompt on Richard alone before \"Lionheart\"]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Richard I</u></b> [accept <b><u>Richard alone</u></b> after \"Lionheart; accept <b><u>Richard the Lionhearted</u></b> before mention; prompt on <u>Richard alone</u> before \"Lionheart]", "acceptable": ["Richard I", "Richard alone", "Richard the Lionhearted"], "promptable": ["Richard alone"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A mathematician from this country used his namesake summation technique to assign the value of -1/12 to the sum of all positive integers. It's not the UK, but that mathematician discovered and was the namesake of the second smallest taxicab number, 1729. Another mathematician from this country names a formula that can be used to calculate the area of a (*) cyclic quadrilateral using its semi-perimeter. A scientist from this country names a mass limit after which electron degeneracy pressure can\u2019t resist the collapse of a white dwarf. For 10 points, name this home country of Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar, Srinivasa (\"sr-ee-nee-vaa-suh\") Ramanujan, and Brahmagupta.", "answer": "Republic of India [accept Bharat Ganrajya]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>India</u></b> [accept <b><u>Bharat Ganrajya</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Republic of India", "Bharat Ganrajya"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one novel by this author, Snowman wakes up in a tree in a post-apocalyptic world and takes care of a group of genetically engineered children who were designed by one of the title figures. This author detailed Alex Thomas' affair with Iris Chase in their novel The Blind Assassin. This author of Oryx and Crake retold the (*) Odyssey from a female perspective in the Penelopiad. In her most famous novel, Nick is a member of the Mayday resistance, and the protagonist illegally plays Scrabble with the Commander. For 10 points, what Canadian author wrote about the dystopian Republic of Gilead and Offred in her novel The Handmaid's Tale?", "answer": "Margaret Eleanor Atwood", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Margaret Eleanor <b><u>Atwood</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Margaret Eleanor Atwood"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This artist\u2019s first track, Too Much Cash, was produced by Nick Mira. In a song by this artist, they rap, \"What\u2019s the 27 club? We ain\u2019t making it past 21,\" a line referencing the deaths of XXXTentacion (\"X-X-X-ten-tah-see-own\") and Lil Peep. This artist's first hit, (*) \"All Girls are the Same,\" was part of his first album, Goodbye and Good Riddance. This artist\u2019s first posthumous appearance was on Eminem\u2019s \"Godzilla,\" where he raps \"Monster, you get in my way, imma (\"EYE-muh\") feed you to the monster.\" The hashtag #LLJW began to trend after this artist\u2019s death on December 8th, 2019. For 10 points, name this artist who released Lucid Dreams.", "answer": "Juice WRLD [or Jarad Anthony Higgins]", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Juice WRLD</u></b> [or <b><u>Jarad Anthony Higgins</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Juice WRLD", "Jarad Anthony Higgins"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The corvus helped one side win the Battle of Mylae (\"my-lye\") in one of these wars. The losing side in one of these conflicts had to fight the Mercenary Wars, and the leader of that side had his brother's head thrown into his camp after that man was killed at the Battle of Metaurus River. The second of these conflicts was started after the Siege of (*) Saguntum, and one side in these conflicts employed the Fabian Strategy. After that strategy fell out of use, the other side used double envelopment to win the Battle of Cannae. Scipio Africanus defeated Hannibal at the Battle of Zama in, for 10 points, what series of wars in which Rome fought against Carthage?", "answer": "Punic Wars", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Punic Wars</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Punic Wars"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This quantity is roughly the same for all liquids at their boiling point according to Trouton's rule. For a black hole, this quantity is proportional to the surface area of the event horizon. This value for a monatomic ideal gas can be found with the Sackur-Tetrode equation. One equation states that this value is equal to (*) Boltzmann's constant times the natural log of the amount of microstates. One law governing this quantity is violated by Maxwell's Demon, and that law, which states that the value for this quantity of the universe is always increasing, is the Second Law of Thermodynamics. For 10 points, what quantity symbolized S measures the disorder of a system?", "answer": "entropy [prompt on S before mention]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>entropy</u></b> [prompt on <u>S</u> before mention]", "acceptable": ["entropy"], "promptable": ["S"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}